Guide to the Women's Refugee Commission Records, 1979-2020; 1979-ongoing, bulk 1989-2011 RL.01405
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Women's Refugee Commission records
1979-2020; 1979-ongoing
1989-2011
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Women's Refugee Commission
RL.01405
55.6 Linear Feet
0.92 Gigabytes
The Women's Refugee Commission was established in 1989 as part of the International Rescue Committee. It advocates for laws, policies, and programs to improve the lives and protect the rights of refugee and internally displaced women, children, and adolescents. Collection includes audiovisual materials (interviews, Voices of Courage luncheons, and footage and photographs from trips to refugee camps); field and research reports; children, education, and youth program materials; foundation files; former board and commission member files; Reproductive Health program materials and reports; Livelihoods program materials and reports; files from executive directors; subject files; board of directors files; and media binders for the Women's Refugee Commission. Countries represented include Cambodia, Afghanistan, Uganda, Sudan, Ethiopia, Kenya, Thailand, Myanmar, Israel, Guatemala, the Democratic Republic of the Congo, Pakistan, Liberia, Kosovo, Iraq, Zambia, Tanzania, the United States, and others. Material predating the founding of the Commission primarily includes photographs from UNHCR and other organizations. Acquired as part of the Human Rights Archive.
36,200 Items
Access Restrictions
Original audiovisual materials are closed to use. Contact Research Services for the production of listening or viewing copies.
In addition, the Reproductive Health Program Series and Washington DC Office Files Series are restricted: patrons must have prior permission to access all or parts of these series. Please review the access notes for each individual series and contact Rubenstein Research Services for information on obtaining permission to access these series.
Collection contains electronic records that may need to be reformatted. Access copies of electronic records must be accessed in our reading room. Contact Research Services for access.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Women's Refugee Commission records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2009, 2010, 2011, 2012, and 2016.
Historical Note
The Women's Refugee Commission, originally known as the Women's Commission for Refugee Women and Children, was founded in 1989 by Catherine O'Neill, Liv Ullmann, Susan Forbes Martin, and Susan Stark, with the support of the International Rescue Committee (IRC). Mary Anne Schwalbe served as the founding director, from 1989 to 1994. She was followed by executive directors Mary Diaz, 1994-2004, Carolyn Makinson, 2004-2010, and Sarah Costa, 2010 to the present. The organization aims "to ensure that the voices of refugee women are heard and to provide these women and their families with the best opportunities for safe, productive lives and a future without fear."
Today there are several programs within the Women's Refugee Commission, including Reproductive Health, Fuel & Firewood Initiative, Livelihoods, Youth, Disabilities, Detention & Asylum, and Gender. To address the needs of displaced women, children, and youth, the WRC staff works with local humanitarian groups to document best practices, propose solutions, and lobby for improvements in refugee policies and protections within the United States and at the United Nations.
For more information on the activities and history of the Women's Refugee Commission, visit their website: www.womensrefugeecommission.org
Collection Overview
The collection is organized into several series, each representing different operations within the Women's Refugee Commission.
The Audiovisual Materials series includes tapes in a variety of formats documenting speaking engagements, luncheons, and interviews with WRC staff; raw footage of trips to refugee camps and field visits with refugees around the world; and recordings of testimony and other projects highlighting the experiences of refugee women and children. This series also includes over 5,000 photographs, slides, and negatives documenting trips to refugee camps and the activities of refugees around the world. Access is RESTRICTED: use copies are required for access.
The Printed Materials and Publications series consists largely of the publications and documentation produced by the Women's Refugee Commission staff about refugee conditions in crisis situations around the world. Trip reports constitute a large portion within the series, covering visits to refugee camps in Africa, Asia, Europe, South America, and United States prisons (where asylum seekers are detained). Also included are public reports and guidelines on issues like domestic and gender-based violence; reproductive health and the Minimum Initial Service Package (MISP); armed conflict and its effects on children; and fuel alternatives and strategies. Drafts of publications, newsletters from the WRC, and a small amount of drawings by refugee children make up the rest of this series.
The Children, Youth, and Education series includes a variety of materials from that WRC program, including additional reports and guidelines. A large component consists of reports, meetings, and other files from the Education in Emergencies initiative.
The Foundations series includes name files for various foundations, trusts, and charities who support the operations of the Women's Refugee Commission. Also included are name files for former board members and commissioners.
Protection Program is a small series with materials from the Women, Peace, and Security (WPS) group and meeting files from the Commission on the Status of Women (CSW).
The Reproductive Health series is a large series with several subseries, all relating to the activities of the Reproductive Health program. One such subseries is the Reproductive Health Response in Conflict (RHRC) Consortium's historical documents, which includes meeting files, conference and event materials, annual reports, and some photographs. Another subseries is United States government-funded projects, covering HIV/AIDS and gender-based violence. Emergency Obstetric Care (EmOC) projects, Thai-Burma border trafficking research, donor files, and subgrantee files make up the remainder of the series. The majority of the Reproductive Health series is restricted.
The Media series consists of newspaper clippings and printouts regarding refugee sitations and the Women's Refugee Commission's coverage in the media.
The Social Protection and Livelihoods series includes program materials and evaluations, with heavy documentation for the Age, Gender and Diversity Mainstreaming (AGDM) Initiative project and its various implementations around the world. Also included in this series are reports and research relating to the Livelihoods program, WRC general information and materials, strategic planning for the group, and board and delegation visits, meetings, and agendas.
The Subject Files series includes topical files primarily related to refugee women and their organizations; issues, such internal displacement, habitat, literacy, and resettlement; the Commission's participation and protection project; and education, especially in emergencies and for girls and adolescents. Other files are related to the Commission's partners in refugee work.
The Executive Director Files series includes materials from Executive Directors Mary Diaz, Carolyn Makinson, and Sarah Costa, such as summary reports and correspondence from all of the WRC programs, UN Security Council Resolutions and other WRC-related initiatives, Board of Director meeting packets, and files for individual board members, commissioners, experts, and fundraisers.
The Board of Directors (BOD) Files series contains primarily board member packets and planning documents for Commission board meetings between 1997-2014. Some board member packets also contain Advocacy Day materials. There are also items related to the Excecutive and Nominating Committee meetings, as well as packets on specialized topics, such as peace initiatives and the Bureau of Public Affairs in the U.S. Department of State. There are a few files related to Board mailings, donors, and potential commissioners.
D.C. Office Files are CLOSED for 20 years (until 2031) unless prior permission is received from the donor. The series includes files on Haiti, Gender, Detention and Asylum, and other programs run through the D.C. office.
The New York Office Files includes material related to the rebranding of the Commission's logo and general design issues, planning anniversary celebrations, launches for reports and book publications, and general files on communications and accountability working groups.
Acronyms frequently used in the collection:
AGDM: Age Gender Diversity Mainstreaming
CSW: Commission on the Status of Women
EmOC: Emergency Obstetric Care
GBV: Gender-based Violence
INS: Immigration and Naturalization Service (US)
IRC: International Rescue Committee
MISP: Minimum Initial Service Package
RH: Reproductive Health
RHC: Reproductive Health in Crises
RHRC: Reproductive Health Response in Conflict Consortium
SIPA: School of International and Public Affairs, Columbia University
UNFPA: United Nations Population Fund
UNHCR: United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees
WPS: Women, Peace, and Security
WRC: Women's Refugee Commission
Videotapes; Reproductive health -- Asia; Internally displaced persons; Refugee children; Reproductive health -- Europe; Asylum, Right of; Refugees -- Abuse of; Refugees -- Legal status, laws, etc.; Women refugees; Refugee camps; Refugees -- Europe; Reproductive health -- Africa; Refugees -- Africa; Refugees -- Asia; Photographs; Slides (photographs); Negatives (photographs); Women's Refugee Commission
- Audiovisual Materials Series, 28 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  The Audiovisual Materials series includes tapes in a variety of formats documenting speaking engagements, luncheons, and interviews with WRC staff; footage of trips to refugee camps and field visits with refugees around the world; and recordings of testimony and other projects highlighting the experiences of refugee women and children. Formats include: VHS, Hi8 Video, MiniDV, VHS C, Betacam, BetacamSP, DVCam, DVD, CD and audio cassette tape. This series also includes a small section of slides.
  There are also over 5000 photographs, slides, and negatives of documenting trips to refugee camps and activities of refugees around the world.
  Box 49 of this series is from Accession 2012-0150 Boxes 62-78 of this series are from Accession 2016-0110
  Conditions Governing Access note
  RESTRICTED: Original audiovisual materials are closed to use. Use of these materials may require production of listening or viewing copies. Please contact Research Services before coming to use this collection.
  Collection contains electronic records that may need to be reformatted. Access copies of electronic records must be accessed in our reading room. Contact Research Services for access
  - Liv Ullmann, February 8, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Public Service Announcements with Liv Ullmann (Box 1)
  - West Africa, August-October 2000 (2 tapes) (Box 1)
  - Liv Ullmann, post-symposium statements, June 10, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Delegation to Croatia and Bosnia, September 1992 (Box 1, Video-cassette RL01405-VHS-0010, Digital-materials RL01405-SET-0010, Video-file RL01405-VHS-0010.mov)
  - Refugee Experience (Box 1)
  - Voices of Courage Awards, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Voices, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Luncheon, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Sudan, September 1998 (Box 1)
  - Assisting Refugee Women (Box 1, Video-cassette RL01405-VHS-0006, Digital-materials RL01405-SET-0010, Video-file RL01405-VHS-0006.mov)
  - Liberty Denied: Asylum and Detention in the U.S., 2003 (Box 1)
  - Refugee Families, JFK Library (Box 1, Video-cassette RL01405-VHS-0008, Digital-materials RL01405-SET-0010, Video-file RL01405-VHS-0008.mov)
  - Refugee Women Protection (Box 1, Video-cassette RL01405-VHS-0009, Digital-materials RL01405-SET-0010, Video-file RL01405-VHS-0009.mov)
  - Rape in Bosnia camps, December 17, 1992 (Box 1, Video-cassette RL01405-VHS-0011, Digital-materials RL01405-SET-0010, Video-file RL01405-VHS-0011.mov)
  - Women and Protection (Box 1)
  - Liv Ullmann acceptance speech: Voices of Courage Award, 1999 (Box 1)
  - U.S. Detention and Asylum (Box 1)
  - Youth Participation Panel: CAC, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Portraits, June 1998 (Box 1)
  - Hear Our Voices: UN Special Session on Children, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Repatriation Symposium: Going Home (Box 1)
  - Ethiopian and Eritrean Delegation, May 29, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Children of War, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Refugee Youth Speak Out (Box 1)
  - Albania, April 1999 (Box 1)
  - Footage from Sudan, August 2003 (2 tapes) (Box 1)
  - Fending for Themselves: Afghan Refugee Children and Adolescents Working in Urban Pakistan (Box 1, Video-cassette RL01405-VHS-0007, Digital-materials RL01405-SET-0010, Video-file RL01405-VHS-0007.mov)
  - Central American Delegation, May 1992 (Box 1)
  - Mission to Chad, January 2005 (2 tapes) (Box 1)
  - Refugee Women Forum: CSW Dialogue, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Panel for CSW, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Refugee Women and Peace, May 2002 (2 tapes) (Box 1)
  - A Child's Right: Education in Emergencies, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Dateline: Veil of Tears, March 1999 (Box 1)
  - Other Voices, September 1994 (Box 1)
  - Voices of Courage, 2002-2003 (2 microcassettes) (Box 1)
  - Luncheon, 1998 and 2000 (2 microcassettes) (Box 1)
  - Cambodian refugee testimony (Box 1)
  - Delegation to Croatia and Bosnia, September 1992 (Box 2)
  - Ethiopia delegation, May 1992 (2 tapes) (Box 2)
  - Liv Ullmann: Refugee Public Service Announcements (Box 2)
  - Central American delegation: Carmen Tellazas, March 1992 (Box 2)
  - Bravo Arene: Liv Ullmann, March 1999 (Box 2)
  - Women Refugee Project, November 1991 (3 tapes) (Box 2)
  - Mary Moran, Public Health: Ethiopia delegation, April 1992 (Box 2)
  - Dr. Shana Swiss, November 1991 (2 tapes) (Box 2)
  - Public Service Announcements (Box 3)
  - Molly Meyers: Central American delegation, March 1992 (Box 3)
  - Mary Talbot: Central American delegation, March 1992 (Box 3)
  - Dawn Calabia interview (Box 3)
  - Dawn Calabia: Central American delegation, March 1992 (2 tapes) (Box 3)
  - Roseanne Murphy, November 1991 (Box 3)
  - Pakistan, January 2002 (Box 3)
  - Hanoi-Hoa Binh (The Thai People) (Box 3)
  - Mary Anne Schwalbe, November 1991 (Box 3)
  - Voices cut: Michael Lerned (Box 3)
  - Voices of Courage Awards, May 2005 (Box 3)
  - Mission to Chad, January 2005 (Box 3)
  - Mary Diaz, April 2001 (Box 3)
  - Voices: Michael Lerned, March 1992 (3 tapes) (Box 4)
  - Women's Commission narration voiceover: Pippa, January 1992 (Box 4)
  - Voices of Courage Awards, May 2006 (Box 4)
  - Ethiopia delegation slides (tape) (Box 4)
  - Maha Muna, Pakistan, December 2001 (Box 4)
  - Voices of Courage Awards luncheon, May 1998 (Box 4)
  - Winifred Barby: Liberia; Mary Diaz: Women's Commission, April 2001 (Box 4)
  - Voices of Courage Awards, May 2004 (Box 4)
  - Somali refugees in Kenya (Box 4)
  - Footage from delegation to Cambodia (Box 4)
  - Hillary Clinton remarks at the Voices of Courage luncheon, May 1999 (Box 4)
  - Thailand, October 1997 (Box 4)
  - Voices of Courage, May 1999 (Box 4)
  - Mission to Chad, January 2005 (3 tapes) (Box 4)
  - Vanessa Redgrave and Wendy Young-Bakersfield, September 1997; Panel discussion, January 1998 (Box 4)
  - CSW Dialogue: Women in Armed Conflict, March 1998 (Box 4)
  - Slide transfer (Box 4)
  - Vis.T.C., September 1991 (Box 4)
  - Women's Commission, November 1998 (Box 4)
  - Repatriation, May 1993 (Box 4)
  - The Refugee Experience, May 1994 (2 tapes) (Box 4)
  - Women's Commission stills, August 1994 (Box 4)
  - Public Service Announcements, January 1997 (Box 4)
  - Bellagio Conference, Taking Care (Box 4)
  - Liv Ullmann interview, December 1991 (4 tapes) (Box 5)
  - Liberty Denied: Asylum and Detention in the U.S., May 2003 (Box 5)
  - Catherine O'Neill Show, December 2003 (Box 5)
  - Kosovo Youth Research Rollout, January 2001 (Box 5)
  - Laos, October 1998 (3 tapes) (Box 5)
  - Liv Ullmann Public Service Announcements (Box 5)
  - A Tribute to Mary Diaz, October 2003 (Box 5)
  - Voices of Courage: Refugee Youth Speak Out, June 2000 (Box 5)
  - Education in Emergencies, 2006 (Box 5)
  - Voices master reel, April 1992 (Box 5)
  - Dr. Shana Swiss, Part One, 17 Nov. 1991 (Box 37)
  - Dr. Shana Swiss, Part Two, 17 Nov. 1991 (Box 37)
  - Linda Hartke, Part One, 18 Nov. 1991 (Box 37)
  - Ethiopia Delegation, 13 Apr. 1992 (Box 37)
  - Ethiopia Delegation Judy Mayotte, 13 Apr. 1992 (Box 37)
  - Leo Cherne Repratriation Statement, 8 June 1992 (Box 37)
  - Somalia No. 1 Submaster, 3 Feb. 1993 (Box 37)
  - Marc Leif Interview with Kiev Chinh Tape No. 3, 31 Mar. 1994 (Box 37)
  - Charlie Rose Bosnia Panel, 17 Apr. 1996 (Box 37)
  - Mahira Tanovic & Kids, 24 Apr. 1998 (Box 37)
  - Portraits, June 1998 (Box 37)
  - Women's Commission Voices of Courage Luncheon No. 2, 13 May 1999 (Box 37)
  - Voices of Courage Refugee Youth Speakout, 1 June 2000 (Box 37)
  - Voice of Courage Awards Backup, 11 May 2006 (Box 37)
  - HIL-19 - stills, undated (Box 37)
  - Public Service Spots, undated (Box 37)
  - WC Chad (Tape No. 3), undated (Box 37)
  - No label, undated (Box 37)
  - Day 1 Gulu Training, 2001 (Box 38)
  - Iraqi Refugees in Jordan, 2007 (Box 38, Video-cassette RL01405-MDV-0006, Digital-materials RL01405-SET-0010, Video-file RL01405-MDV-0006.dv)
  - Interview Nana Apeadu Tape 4, 23 Sept. 1991 (Box 38)
  - WRP Hr 3 Susan Forbes Martin, 14 Nov. 1991 (Box 38)
  - Anne Goldfried, 16 Nov. 1991 (Box 38)
  - Beverlee Bruce, 21 Nov. 1991 (Box 38)
  - Dawn Calabia WCRWC, 19 Feb. 1992 (Box 38)
  - Mary Talbot Central American Delegation, 26 Feb. 1992 (Box 38)
  - Carmen Fellazas Central American Delegation, 5 Mar. 1992 (Box 38)
  - Ethiopia Eritrea Delegation, 15 Apr. 1992 (Box 38)
  - Voiceover Reel Pippa-Repratriation, 29 May 1992 (Box 38)
  - Somalia HR-0, 3 Feb. 1993 (Box 38)
  - Liv Ullman PSA, 13 June 1993 (Box 38)
  - Women's Commission No. 2 Anne Goldfeld, Lilieu Brown, 25 July 1993 (Box 38)
  - Dr. Pat Walker Cambodia 2, 26 July 1993 (Box 38)
  - Sierra Leone, 1 Mar. 1996 (Box 38)
  - Macenta - West Africa, 1 Mar. 1997 (Box 38)
  - Sierra Leone 4, 20 Mar. 1997 (Box 38)
  - RW/BUT and Kakuma No. 4, 24 Apr. 1997 (Box 38)
  - Pakistan, 1 June 1997 (Box 38)
  - Nana Apadeau, Beverlee Bruce, 27 July 1998 (Box 38)
  - Day 5 Mahusot Hospital, 23 Oct. 1998 (Box 38)
  - April 1999 in Albania, Apr. 1999 (Box 38)
  - WC Tributes 1, Catherine Oneill, Bob, Beverly Bruce, 13 Apr. 1999 (Box 38)
  - Women's Commission VOC Luncheon No. 1, 13 May 1999 (Box 38)
  - BUBANZA, 1 Oct. 2000 (Box 38)
  - Burundi Delegation, 1 Oct. 2000 (Box 38)
  - WC Interviews, Nama-Sierra Leone, Emil-Kosovo, 17 Apr. 2001 (Box 38)
  - Wendy Smith, Wendy Smith, Alxhere Veseli, Ayuba, 17 Apr. 2001 (Box 38)
  - Adol Research Presentation Gulu, Uganda, 1 Nov. 2001 (Box 38)
  - Afghanistan: Panel, 1 Nov. 2001 (Box 38)
  - Gulu Training Kampala, 9 Nov. 2001 (Box 38)
  - Maha Muna Pakistan, 1 Dec. 2001 (Box 38)
  - Centerfast Children and Women Peshawer Carpentry Kids - Pakistan 2, Jan. 2002 (Box 38)
  - Pakistan Peshawer scenes I, Jan. 2002 (Box 38)
  - Wess and Quetta City Depot Peshawer Pakistan 3, Jan. 2002 (Box 38)
  - Video for 4th Luncheon, Leadership Council on Children in Armed Conflict, 22 Feb. 2002 (Box 38)
  - Promoting the Protection and Capacities of Adolescents in Sierra Leone Project-Freetown training, 6 Apr. 2002 (Box 38)
  - Sierra Leone-Makeni Research, 15 Apr. 2002 (Box 38)
  - Ad Study Sierra Leone Makeni, 24 Apr. 2002 (Box 38)
  - Pakistan Rev Cut, 23 July 2002 (Box 38)
  - Haiti DR, Sept. 2002 (Box 38)
  - Precious Resources Launch Makeni Reintegration Drama, 29 Oct. 2002 (Box 38)
  - Precious Resources Launch Makeni Sierra Leone, 29 Oct. 2002 (Box 38)
  - Precious Resources Launch Freetown, Sierra Leone 1, Nov. 2002 (Box 38)
  - Precious Resources Launch Freetown, Sierra Leone 2, Nov. 2002 (Box 38)
  - Sierra Leone Kids In US CAP, Nov. 2002 (Box 38)
  - Precious Resources Launch New York City 1, 4 Nov. 2002 (Box 38)
  - Precious Resources Launch New York City 2, 4 Nov. 2002 (Box 38)
  - Ermias Interview, Ermias, B-roll, Aster interview, 15 Apr. 2003 (Box 38)
  - Liberty Denied: Asylum and Detention in the US, 2 May 2003 (Box 38)
  - Afghanistan/Pakistan- Peshawar AWN journalist training 1, Oct. 2003 (Box 38)
  - Afghanistan/Pakistan 2, Oct. 2003 (Box 38)
  - Mission to Chad, 14 Feb. 2005 (Box 38)
  - What Happens When I Go To Immigration Court?, 9 Oct. 2005 (Box 38)
  - Thailand Delegation 1, 22 June 2006 (Box 38)
  - Thailand Delegation 2, 22 June 2006 (Box 38)
  - Ban Interview Amman, Jordan, 11 June 2007 (Box 38, Video-cassette RL01405-MDV-0007, Digital-materials RL01405-SET-0010, Video-file RL01405-MDV-0007.dv)
  - Suaad Interview Amman Jordan, 11 June 2007 (Box 38)
  - Rajaa Interview Amman Jordan, 12 June 2007 (Box 38)
  - Random Shots in Iraqi Homes Amman Jordan, 12 June 2007 (Box 38, Video-cassette RL01405-MDV-0009, Digital-materials RL01405-SET-0010, Video-file RL01405-MDV-0009.dv)
  - Iraqi Refugee Mother Amman Jordan, 13 June 2007 (Box 38, Video-cassette RL01405-MDV-0008, Digital-materials RL01405-SET-0010, Video-file RL01405-MDV-0008.dv)
  - Iraqi Refugee Widow and Young Girl, 13 June 2007 (Box 38, Video-cassette RL01405-MDV-0010, Digital-materials RL01405-SET-0010, Video-file RL01405-MDV-0010.dv)
  - Eva Interview Amman Jordan, 18 June 2007 (Box 38)
  - City Scenes in Amman, Jordan, 22 June 2007 (Box 38, Video-cassette RL01405-MDV-0011, Digital-materials RL01405-SET-0010, Video-file RL01405-MDV-0011.dv)
  - Disabilities Report Launch, 23 June 2008 (Box 38)
  - Catherine O'Neil WCRC, 2 Dec., no year (Box 38)
  - Liv Ullman, 11 Dec., no year (Box 38)
  - Uganda Adol in USA, Fall 2001 (Box 38)
  - Rwanda Memorial No. 3, undated (Box 38)
  - South Sudan -1199, undated (Box 38)
  - Repatraiation Symposium: Going Home, undated (Box 38)
  - Maryanne's Discourse Tape 3, undated (Box 38)
  - Shogufa 1, undated (Box 38)
  - WCRWC Public Service Spots, undated (Box 38)
  - Refugee Youth Chat 3, undated (Box 38)
  - Soul II Soul Make a Little Difference UNHCR, undated (Box 38)
  - You Are the Only One, undated (Box 38)
  - No label, undated (Box 38)
  - Shogufa 2, undated (Box 38)
  - Sima Wali, undated (Box 38)
  - 1999 Voice of Courage Awards: Liv Ullmann Acceptance Speech, 1999 (Box 39)
  - A tribute to Mary Diaz, 26 June 2005 (Box 39)
  - Desperate and Alone: Refugee Women and Youth in Jordan, 29 June 2005 (Box 39)
  - The Health Care Crisis for Iraqi Refugee Women & Girls, 29 June 2005 (Box 39)
  - Violence Against Women & Girls in the Iraq Crisis, 29 June 2005 (Box 39)
  - Voice of Courage Honoree Shreen Abdul Saroor, 30 June 2005 (Box 39)
  - Women's Commission Retreat Tape No. 2, 21 Sept. 1991 (Box 39)
  - Women's Commission Retreat Tape No. 1, 21 Sept. 1991 (Box 39)
  - Diana Bui, Courtney Pasterfield, Washington, 16 Oct. 1991 (Box 39)
  - Dia Cha Interview, Flagstaff, 11 Nov. 1991 (Box 39)
  - Dawn Calabia Int., 13 Nov. 1991 (Box 39)
  - Dr. Shana Swiss, 17 Nov. 1991 (Box 39)
  - Bob DeVeedi NYC, 20 Nov. 1991 (Box 39)
  - Catherine O'Neil WCRC, 2 Dec. 1991 (Box 39)
  - Dawn Calabia Central American Delegation, 19 Feb. 1992 (Box 39)